人人影视
YYeTs.com
原创翻译  双语字幕
■
仅供学习 禁止用于任何商业盈利行为
更多影视更新
请登陆www.YYeTs.com
翻译：Iz    红豆包    奈奈良  Bazinga
校对：Iz          总监   IZ
时间轴：今        后期：吉吉
《开心汉堡店》
第三季第十六集
跟我说实话  我是不是除了激光枪
Okay, tell me the truth,
狗叫和放屁的声音  再难以有突破了
am I stuck in a laser/dog bark/fart rut?
-不会  -是的
- No. - Yes.
有人看见我的火山没
Has anyone seen my volcano?
你有没有翻遍所有的口袋
Did you check all your pockets?
你能描述一下它长什么样吗
Can you describe what it looks like?
它是火山的形状
Well, it's volcano-shaped,
是我去年的科学展课题项目
and it's my science fair project from last year.
在酒柜里
Oh, it's in the liquor cabinet.
我一直把它当瓶托使来着
I've been using it as a wine koozie.
很有意思  我喜欢
It's fun, I love it.
介绍一下我今年的科学展项目
Introducing my science fair project for this year.
等等
Hold on.
等等  你又交同样的项目吗
Wait, you're turning in the same project again?
布莱文斯老师会让你这么做吗
Will Mr. Blevins let you do that?
是啊  露易丝  他不仅是老师
Yeah, Louise, he's not just a teacher,
还是科学展的负责人哦
he's the head of the science fair.
肯定有好多女人向他投怀送抱
He must be swimming in women.
布莱文斯那边就不用担心了
Don't worry about Blevins.
他就像我手中梳着马尾  长着难看屁股
I can play him like a fiddle.
发了幅的小提琴  搞定他易如反掌
A strange, puffy fiddle with a ponytail and a sad butt.
露易丝  你难道不该按要求
Louise, shouldn't you just do a new project,
-做个新的项目吗  -为什么
- like you're supposed to? - Why?
我不知道  学点东西
Um, I don't know, to learn something?
你自己学去吧
You learn something.
好吧  亲爱的  祝你好运
Okay honey, good luck with your volcano.
123,
124...
你们这两个呆瓜在干嘛
What are you two kooks doing?
这是我们的科学展项目
It's for our science fair project:
"我头上有多少根头发"
"How Many Hairs Are Up There?"
最难的部分就是把它们摆整齐
The tough part is keeping them all organized.
我得
I ga... Oh!
-一  二  -你们俩太认真了
- One, two... - You guys are working too hard.
一点没变
As per "Uuge."
早上好  孩子们
Good morning, children.
我是丁克勒老师
My name is Mr. Dinkler,
以后将由我来为大家上科学课
and I will be taking over this science class.
什么
Whoa, whoa whoa, what?
布莱文斯老师去哪儿了
What happened to Mr. Blevins?
他死了
He's dead.
对你们来说
To this classroom.
他痛风病发作  这会儿正在家里疗养
He's at home recovering from a severe attack of gout.
我不想再提他了  我们直接进入正题吧
But I'm sick of talking about him, so let's just move on already.
周二晚上去过科学博物馆的人
Some of you might recognize me if you've been down
也许能认出我来
to the Science Museum on Tuesday nights.
我是托马斯・爱迪生的模仿者和扮演者
I am a Thomas Edison impersonator and reenactor.
托马斯・爱迪生是有史以来
Thomas Edison was the greatest
-最伟大的天才  -我去
- genius who ever lived. - Oh, boy.
有人能说出他的发明吗
Can anyone name any of his inventions?
-电灯炮  -电灯泡
- The lightbulb... - The lightbulb.
留声机
The phonograph.
放映机
The kinetoscope.
还有很多很多  不胜枚举
It goes on and on and on, basically everything.
我知道四年级的科学展快到了
So, I know the fourth grade science fair
因为现在我是负责人了
is coming up, because I'm in charge of it now.
我对科学展只有一个规定
I only have one rule for science fairs:
火  山  不  行
No vol-ca-noes.
多年来一直有人想用那些硬纸板做的
Kids have been using these papier-matcher monstrosities
奇形怪状的东西蒙混过关  我可不买帐
to avoid real work for years, and I'll have none of it.
丁克勒先生  先暂停一下
Okay, Mr. Dinkler, time out.
别着急
Relax.
布莱文斯先生已经同意我
I already got the go-ahead
做火山了
from Mr. Blevins on my volcano.
可以说我基本上不归你管了
So, I'm kind of grandfathered in there.
你叫什么名字  小姑娘
What is your name, young lady?
露易丝
It's Louise,
"天哪  露易丝  你太棒了"的露易丝
as in "Jeez, Louise, you're the best."
我们给你想个新的项目怎么样
Why don't we find you another topic?
不  没有那个必要
Oh, no, that's not necessary.
我已经有了
I already got it.
我帮你选一个
I'll pick one for you.
没必要  我已经有了
Don't need to, I got one.
-有必要  -非常感谢
- Yeah... - Thank you so much.
不行  我就要选一个
Nope, gonna pick one.
这可是世界上最棒的课题项目
And it's the best topic in the world:
托马斯・爱迪生
Thomas Edison!
但我正在做托马斯・爱迪生的项目
Um, but I'm doing Thomas Edison.
你们可以同时做啊  小笨蛋
You can both do Edison, moron.
相信我  爱迪生的素材可多着呢
There's enough of him to go around, trust me.
丁克勒先生  鉴于你刚来
Mr. Dinkler, you're new here,
如果我无视你的每一句话  一意孤行地
so please don't be offended if I disregard
交我的"露易丝山"  请不要感到冒犯
everything you say and turn in Mt. Louise-ius here.
我猜一定真的有东西
Wow, I bet stuff comes out of the top
从上面这个洞冒出来  简直酷毙了
where this hole is and it's just a real hoot.
-没错  -不
- Yeah. - Oh, no.
我把它扔地上干嘛呢
Why did I throw that down? Wha...
-还要踩几下  -不要
- Oh, wha... I'm stepping on it? - No!
我为什么要踩它
Why am I stepping on it?
-一遍又一遍地蹂躏它呢  -别这样
- Over and over and over again. - Stop it!
给我做爱迪生的项目  孩子
You're doing Edison, kid.
下面我们来学点科学知识吧
How about some science, huh?
真不敢相信他居然那样对我
Ugh, I can't believe that guy.
现在我不得不去图书馆了
And now I have to go to the library,
我从来没想过要去那种地方
which I never wanted to have to do.
-烦人  -没错  烦人
- Ugh! - Yeah, ugh!
等等  我挺喜欢图书馆的
Wait, I like the library.
我需要托马斯・爱迪生的资料
I need information on Thomas Edison.
那种就算我剽窃也不会被发现的资料
Something no one would recognize if plagiarized.
看传记吧  在"E"书架
Biographies, under "E."
多谢
Thanks.
我应该做的
That's my job.
我热爱我的工作  托普西
And I love it. Topsy.
我啥也没说
I didn't say anything.
托  普  西
Tooooopsssyyyyy.
你是在说"顶级厨师"吗
Are you saying Top Chef?
我想他说的是托普西
I think he said Topsy.
不  我没说  是的  我说了
No, I didn't. Yes, I did.
托普西是什么
What's a Topsy?
我不知道  不要问我
I don't know, don't ask me.
去查查
Look it up.
去书里查么
Like in a book?
当然了  书无所不知
Yeah, sure, books are great.
不  上网查
No, use the Internet.
书里啥都没有
Books are stupid.
我还以为书里应有尽有呢
I thought books were smart.
不  啥都没有
No, they're stupid.
但你可是图书管理员啊
But you're a librarian.
是的  小点声
Yeah, so shh!
托普西
Hmm. Topsy.
看  马戏团大象托普西
Look, Topsy the circus elephant.
托马斯・爱迪生想向世人证明
Thomas Edison wanted to show the world
交流电流
that AC current was more
比他发明的直流电流更危险
dangerous than his own patented DC current...
有视频  点开
Oh, there's a video. Click that.
大象
Ooh, elephant.
我敢说它打喷嚏一定很可爱
I bet it sneezes and it's adorable.
什么情况
What was that?
再播一遍  再播一遍
Play it again, Play it again.
它被人
It was electrocuted.
有意图地  在光天化日下
To death. On purpose.
电死了
In public.
凶手就是托马斯・爱迪生
By Thomas Edison.
啥意思  难道他是超级反派
What is he, a supervillain?
上面说托普西踩死了三个人
Well, it says that Topsy trampled three people.
这也难免  她是一头又肥又壮的大象嘛
Well yeah, she's a big, fat elephant.
关键是  我知道科学展做什么了
The point is, I've got my science fair project.
我要让每一个人都看到
I'm gonna tell everyone
电刑犯爱迪生的真正面目
the truth about Edison the Electro-cutioner.
-说出事实吧  妹妹  -好伟大
- Tell it, sister. - So heroic.
让我说完先
Let me finish!
我还要让丁克勒老师
And make Mr. Dinkler
变成扮演邪恶发明家的混蛋
look like an evil-inventor-impersonating ass.
-这才像你嘛  -好吧
- There she is. - Oh, right.
不要这么做  不要这么做
Don't do it, Don't do it.
做吧  做吧
Do it, do it.
然后我说  "电灯泡  我有主意了
And then I say, "Hey. Lightbulb. I've got an idea.
就是电灯泡
The lightbulb.
我是爱迪生  谢谢"
I'm Edison, thank you."
然后大家都鼓掌了
And everyone claps.
丁克勒老师  我是不是该和露易丝
Mr. Dinkler, shouldn't Louise and I make sure
确认下以免我们的爱迪生课题项目撞车
that we're not both doing the same thing for our Edison project?
我问你  杰里米
Well, let's see, Jeremy.
你的项目会吓大家一跳吗
Is your project going to blow everyone away?
如果不会  你就没必要担心了
'Cause if it's not, then don't worry about it.
有什么好笑的
What's so funny?!
各位  火山妹说要吓我们一跳呢
Hey, everybody, volcano-girl here is gonna blow our minds.
你听到了吗  汤姆
Did you hear that, Tom?
我会的
Well, I will!
我已经有猛料了  丁克勒老师
I've got something big, Mr. Dinkler.
你啥都没有  你自己心知肚明
You ain't got nothing and you know it.
你就一直这么想吧  丁克勒老师
You keep believing that, Mr. Dinkler.
我会的
I will.
你就一直这么想吧  丁克勒老师
You keep believing that, Mr. Dink-ler.
很好  很好
Yes, yes!
很...好笑
Very... funny.
好吧  变更计划
Okay, change of plans.
只是在图画纸上贴一则小新闻
Some little report pasted onto construction paper
太弱了
isn't gonna be enough.
不够让那个老匹夫好看
Not for that punk.
我讨厌图画纸
I hate construction paper.
他既然那么爱演
Dinkler's a reenactor.
那我就演给他看
I'm going reenactment on his butt.
演员啊特效啊  总之用尽一切手段
With actors and effects and everything.
我们要再现那场可怕的噩梦
We're gonna bring this nightmare to life.
好了  我需要两个爱迪生和托普西演员
All right, I'm gonna need an Edison and a Topsy.
吉恩  来个丧心病狂的大笑
Gene, can you give me a maniacal laugh?
好极了  你就是爱迪生了
Good enough, you're Edison.
蒂娜  扮个大象来看看
Tina, act like an elephant.
感觉还行  就你了
Not bad, you're hired.
知道你的项目还缺什么吗
Oh, you know what else your project needs?
科学
Science?
我创作的音乐
Music. By me.
既富有戏剧变化  又包含舞曲元素
Something dramatic, but danceable.
可以  只要我们能电死一头大象
Fine, as long as we electrocute an elephant,
其他我都没意见
it's okay with me.
不是真电击  只是演的  对吧
But not really electrocuting, just reenacting.
是的  蒂娜
Yes, Tina.
真服了你了
Jeesh.
"别真的电死我"圣女姐姐
Little Miss Don't-Really-Electrocute-Me over here. Diva.
你还有什么附加条件没
What else do you want on your rider?
孩子们  你们好
Hello, children.
泰迪是你啊  快过来
Ah, Teddy, come here.
我正在做一个课题项目
I'm doing a project and I need to make
我需要弄出超大的火花和闪电
huge sparks and lightning bolts.
你知道那东西怎么弄吗
What do you know about that stuff?
我高中和哥们儿做过范德格拉夫起电机
In high school, my buddies and I built a Van de Graaff generator.
你懂的  泡马子用嘛
You know, to get girls.
好极了
Ah, nice.
能给我也做一个吗
Will you do something like that for me?
学校不让大人帮忙  所以你要偷偷做
Adults aren't allowed to help, so you'll have to hide.
但...可以吧
But... eh?
可以
Sure.
那走吧
Let's go!
好吧  吃不成汉堡了  没关系
Okay, no burger, that's fine.
我并不是害怕哦
Ahh, I'm not freaking out here!
我记得就放在这里了
I know they're in here somewhere.
鲍勃  上床了
Bob, come to bed.
找到了
Here it is.
孩子们的科技展让我想起我的旧发明
All this science fair stuff reminded me of my old invention.
调料腕带
Spiceps.
调料啥
Spice-wah?
就是把调味料像袖筒一样绑在手臂上
They're sleeves that you wear on your biceps
方便做饭时取用
to hold all your spices while you cook.
快看
Look,.
好吧  晚安
Okay, good night.
琳  要是我只戴这个东西的话
Hey Lin, what if I was wearing just these.
看  我这就脱光光了哦
'Cause, whoop, I am.
好啦  到这来
All right, come here.
这就来
I'm coming.
等等  等等
Wait, wait, wait,
你把调料全撒床上了
you're getting spice all over the bed.
托普西
Topsy...
尸体解剖...
autopsy...
有事吗
Is there something there?
我不能说话  我在演大象
I'm not talking; I'm in character.
不过  我能踩你吗
Except, can I trample you?
我在尽力融入大象的角色
I'm trying to get in that head space.
行  你踩吧
Yeah, sure.
你们看到我的调料腕带没
Did, uh, did you guys notice my Spiceps?
老爸  这会没空
Dad, not now.
切  调料腕带
Pffh, Spiceps.
要是给他来个脱胎换骨的改造
You might have something there,
或许还能像那么回事
if you just changed it completely.
用不着  这样最完美
They're perfect the way they are.
老爸  小点声
Dad, shush.
蒂娜  只要你音准没问题就行了
Okay, Tina, as long as you have perfect pitch, we'll be fine.
一哒哒  二哒哒
And a one, and a two.
*他们会*
* They'll...*
我来了  亲人们
Hello, family.
讨厌
Ugh.
你好  盖尔姨妈
Hi, Aunt Gayle.
盖尔  早先电话里你是怎么了
Hey, Gayle, I couldn't understand you on the phone earlier.
听你声音那样
You sounded like.
一切还好吗
Is everything all right?
我没事
Everything's fine.
只是他有时真是够混蛋的
He can just be such a jerk sometimes.
你说谁  亲爱的  怎么了
Aw, who honey? Wha?
我的猫
My cat.
我们吵架了
We got in a fight.
我能在这冷静冷静吗
Can I stay here for a while to cool off?
当然没问题
Of course you can.
盖尔  看看我
Hey Gayle, check it out.
好吧  回头再说
Okay, talk to you later.
蒂娜  一哒哒  二哒哒
Tina, and a one, and a two.
*他们*
*They'll...*
你们好  贝尔彻一家
Hello, Belchers.
该死
Damn it!
我本不想来打扰的  但你们该交月租了
Don't mean to barge in, just here for the monthly rent.
月租是按月缴的
I say monthly,
我想你们在这点上还没搞清楚
because I think there might be some confusion about that.
费舍奥德先生  你好
Oh, hey, Mr. Fischoeder.
抱歉  我马上写支票给你
Sorry, I'll write you a check right now.
用我的两只胳膊
With my arms.
没必要这么具体的  不过随便吧
Strangely specific, but whatever.
看  刚好有笔  给
Oh, look, a pen. Here.
不用了
I'm good.
要来点胡椒粉吗
Care for any cracked pepper?
百里香呢
How about some thyme?
赶紧写支票
Just write the check.
要不来点马郁兰吧
Perhaps some marjoram?
写支票
Write a check!
那月桂叶怎么样
How about a bay leaf?
一哒哒  二哒哒
And a one, and a two...
*他们会说  我在解剖托普西的尸体*
*They'll say aw, Topsy at my autopsy*
-你知道好笑的是什么吗  -但还没
- Okay, here's a funny story. - But no...
你根本不会唱歌
You cannot sing.
什么
What?
我们必须得换掉你了
Yeah, we're gonna have to replace you.
别  我对这个角色已经有浓厚的感情了
No, I-I have a strong connection to this character.
现在没了吧
And there it goes.
你呢  你会唱吗
Wha-what about you? Can you sing?
那还用说
Ah, yeah.
*他们会说  我在解剖*
*They'll say aw, Topsy at my...*
天哪  我也不会唱
Oh, my God I can't sing either!
我们该怎么办
What are we gonna do?!
这歌很上口呢
That song's catchy.
*他们会说*
*They'll say aw, *
*我在解剖托普西的尸体*
*Topsy at my autopsy.*
的确很上口
It is catchy.
*我在解剖托普西的尸体*
*Aw, Topsy at my auuu-ho-ho-hoopsy*
我的天呀
Holy moly.
你这会儿想的跟我一样吗
Are you thinking what I'm thinking?
让盖尔姨妈和费舍奥德先生安静点吗
That we should ask Aunt Gayle and Mr. Fischoeder to keep it down?
不  让他们帮我们唱
No, we should ask them to sing for us.
但学校的课题项目不许大人参与的
But we're not allowed to use adults in school projects.
我们可以搞米力瓦利合唱团那一套
We're gonna Milli Vanilli this.
德国男声二人组  靠对嘴假唱红透半边天  事发后从云端跌落谷底
抱歉  我不大懂意大利语
Sorry, I don't speak Italian.
我们可以对嘴  对嘴你懂吗
We'll lip sync it! Lip synch it!
所以  这周五你们俩要不要
So... what are you two doing on Friday
来我们学校礼堂躲在帘子后面帮我们唱歌
besides singing from behind a curtain in our school auditorium?
天哪 现在做起饭来容易多了
God, cooking is just too easy now.
在经过周密的构思和一番高超的缝制之后
So, after a lot of thought and some amazing sewing,
我终于帮你的发明做出了改良版  鲍勃
I think I finally fixed your invention, Bob.
它不需要什么改良  所以...
Well, it didn't need fixing, so...
看哪
Ta-da!
这叫调料胸带[调料架]
It's the Spice Rack.
听懂没  架子[俚语胸部]
Get it? Rack.
你看上去真滑稽
Ah, well, you look ridiculous.
-我滑稽  -没错
- Oh, I look ridiculous? - Yeah, you do.
你俩半斤八两
You're both right.
我不过是在你的想法上改良了
I just took your idea and I made it good.
啥  这不叫改良
What? No you didn't.
来  孩儿们  谁的更好
Come on, kids, which is better?
-我不来  -不趟这浑水  谢谢
- Pass. - No, thank you.
蒂娜
Tina?
瞧瞧  我这个如何
Huh, how about this?
这又不是拼谁骚
It's not using sex to sell.
你想要这个吧  我的吧
You want this, right? This one.
你们俩我都一样爱
I love you both equally!
管你爱谁呢
Oh, who cares?!
对不起
Sorry.
我也爱你
I love you, too.
*他也许会电击我*
*He might electrocute me*
*没错*
*That's true*
*但他是电子尤物*
*But he's an electro-cutey*
*哪里哪里*
Aw, shucks.
那...啥...
Um... wha...
AC呼叫DC  DC请回答  完毕
AC to DC, come in, DC, over.
DC收到
DC here.
给我个信号  我就打开开关
Just give me the go-ahead and I'll flip the switch.
你确定我待在这下面是可以的吗
Are you sure I'm allowed to be down here?
不确定  要是你被抓了  咱俩没关系
Nope, so if you get caught, we don't know each other.
*她波涛胸涌*
*Her bosom's mighty ample*
*他帅气逼人  让我难以下脚*
*He's just too hot to trample*
-好了  别演了  -不演了吗
- Okay, okay, stop right there. - We're stopping?
-不是  -是的
- No. - Yes.
剧院就这德性
Ah, the theater.
咱们等的这会儿亲热亲热咋样
Should we fool around back here while we wait?
好啊  先让我舔舔嘴巴
Okay, just let me lick my lips.
算了
Never mind.
吉恩  这歌怎么回事儿
Gene, what the heck is going on with the song?
我们把它改编成了情歌对唱
We made it into a love duet.
你说啥
What?!
我们的目的是要报复丁克乐老师
The whole point of this is to get back at Mr. Dinkler.
或是克服重重困难
Or is it that against all odds,
孤独的发明家和倒霉大象彼此找到了真爱
a lonely inventor and a down-on-her-luck elephant find true love?
别搞了  直接进入电击部分吧
Oh, forget it! Let's just get to the pyro.
蒂娜  站泰迪的瑜伽垫上
Tina, stand on Teddy's yoga mat
别乱动  不然就会
and don't move or it's...
你确定这样安全吗
Are you sure this is safe?
泰迪  告诉蒂娜你的瑜伽垫会保护她
Teddy, tell Tina your yoga mat will keep her safe
因为那是橡胶做的  完毕
because it's rubber, over.
我的...慢着  谁来着
My... wait, who?
蒂娜  她正站在瑜伽垫上
Tina, she's standing on the yoga mat.
咱们能开始了吗
So can we do this?
我们听不清你说啥
Okay, we can't hear you very well.
听我倒计时信号
So let's just go on my count.
三  二  一
Three, two, one!
我的象鼻子
My trunk!
等着我把这事儿告诉丁克勒老师吧
Wait till Mr. Dinkler hears about this.
等着让丁克勒老师见识见识吧
Wait till Mr. Dinkler sees this.
我明白你的意思
Well, I see your point.
是有点危险
It is a little dangerous.
你不必冒这个险
Well, you don't have to do it.
我们可以用吉恩的动物玩具
We can just use one of Gene's stuffed animals.
想必它们也受够吉恩的屁了
I'm sure they're tired of being farted on.
他们爱死了
They love it.
蒂娜  真相必须大白于天下
Tina, people must know the truth.
让历史重演吧
Do the reenactment.
要是我被电死了咋办
But what if I get electrocuted?
拜托  不会那么糟糕啦
Oh, come on, it's not that bad.
-可你就死了啊  -干嘛揭人家伤疤
- But you died. - Well, you don't have to rub it in.
只是  我还没
It's just, I'm not...
蒂娜  告诉人们我的故事
Tina, tell my story.
还有  你偶尔可以试试把头发扎起来
Also, you should wear your hair up sometimes, girlfriend.
那样好看多了
It looks really good.
好吧  托普西  听你的
Okay, Topsy, I'll do it,
不过头发就免了吧
but maybe not the hair thing.
别这样嘛
Oh, come on.
这个长度有点尴尬
It's just awkward with this length.
-试试嘛  -瞧  我现在就扎给你看
- Try it. - See, I'm trying it right now. Look.
你还是放下来吧
You know what, wear it down.
成败在此一举  今天爱迪生和丁克勒
This is it. Today Edison and Dinkler
会为他们那灯泡照不到的阴暗面付出代价
are gonna get it right where the lightbulb don't shine.
你确定不要音乐吗
Are you sure you don't want music?
不用音乐  谢谢
No, no music, thank you.
你本来有机会的  你自己搞砸了
You had your chance and you blew it.
好吧  那我不干了
Fine, then I quit!
随你便
Suit yourself.
现在我觉得被冷落了  让我回去吧
Well, now I feel left out. Take me back.
好吧  欢迎归队
All right, you're rehired.
谢天谢地  谢谢
Oh, thank God. Thank you.
泰迪  咱们的点火装置咋样了
Teddy, what's our pyro status?
问题都解决了吗
Did you work out all the kinks?
我是指你差点把蒂娜给烧化了这件事
And by kinks I mean almost melting Tina.
是的  除了  没啥  肯定没问题的
I think so, except for, uh... Nah, I'm sure it'll be fine.
蒂娜  你干嘛发出那样的声音
Tina, why are you making that noise?
怎么啦  孩子
What is it, girl?
蒂娜只是因为要参加科学展太兴奋了
Oh, Tina's just pumped about the science fair.
我也是耶
Oh, wow, me, too.
大家都准备好要出发了吗
Is everybody ready to go?
你们老爹呢
Where's your father?
我来了
Uh, here I am.
这大包小包的干嘛
What's all that?
就一些我想带到科学展去的东西
Uh, just some stuff I thought I'd bring to the science fair.
你要带调料腕带过去吗
Are you bringing Spiceps?
我只想听听大家的意见  琳
I just want some feedback, Lin.
谁知道呢  说不定哪个有钱的家长
Who knows, maybe there's some wealthy parent
看到后觉得能挣大钱愿意投资呢
that knows a good money-making venture when they see one.
你这是痴心妄想
That's crazy.
我去拿调料胸带
I'm going to get the Spice Rack.
你好  丁克勒老师
Oh, hello, Mr. Dinkler.
真是欣欣向荣的科学日啊
What a day for science, huh?
露易丝
Louise,
要我开开关就给我个口信
give me the word when you want me to hit the switch.
我知道你在捣什么鬼  你个小太妹
I know what you're doing, you hooligan.
杰里米昨晚啥都看见了
Jeremy saw everything last night.
你这打小报告的卑鄙小人
Oh, you son of a snitch!
你最爱看的电影是啥
What's your favorite movie?
《告密木兰花》吗
Squeal Magnolias?!
原为Steel Magnolias《钢木兰花》美国喜剧电影  女人坚不可摧的情谊
-《战马》  -你想败坏爱迪生的名声
- War Horse. - You're trying to sully Edison's good name,
斯皮尔伯格导演电影  男孩与战马之间非同寻常的友谊
没人可以诋毁我的偶像汤姆
and nobody messes with my man, Tom.
你被禁足了
You're banned.
给我进去
Get in there.
你无权阻止我参加科学展
You can't ban me from the science fair.
回见  小白痴
So long, idiot.
校长办公室
我要羞辱你的计划都被打断了
You're ruining my plan to humiliate you!
哎呦老天  那东西倒了  真糟糕
Boy, that, uh, that fell over. Too bad.
这是黄金地段
That's prime real estate.
看着点  有人来了
Watch out, someone's coming.
调料腕带  烹饪的未来
调料胸带  改良版的调料腕带
这作品真不错
Uh, uh, just checking out this great project.
一定是个聪明孩子做的  对吧
This must be a really smart kid, right?
不如这个孩子聪明  她简直是个天才
Not as smart as this kid right here; She's a genius.
是吗  我觉得那孩子偷了这孩子的点子
Oh, really? I think that kid stole this kid's idea
她该准备好吃官司了
and she should probably get a lawyer.
-他才没这胆  -他有
- Oh, he wouldn't dare. - Oh, he would.
我会击垮你的
I will destroy you.
好耶
Hooray!
现在露易丝被关禁闭了
Now that Louise is banned,
就剩我一个爱迪生项目了
I'm the only Edison project.
-杰里米  闭嘴  -好
- Jeremy, shush. - Right.
年轻人  听说你写了首情歌对唱
Young man, I hear you wrote a love duet that dispels those nasty
能驱散电击谣言  体现爱迪生柔情一面
electrocution rumors and shows Edison's softer side.
我觉得科学展需要的就是这个
I think that's just what this science fair needs,
我想让你唱这首歌
and I want you to sing it.
真的吗  太好了
Really? All right!
-什么  -我得去找我的房东和我姨妈
- What? - I've got to call our landlord and my aunt
或许再叫几个唱诗班的孩子和乐队高手
and maybe some choir kids and maybe a couple of band geeks.
如果这是你的庆祝方式  请便
If that's how you celebrate good news, sure.
可是吉恩  露易丝怎么办
But, Gene, what about Louise?
真相又该如何揭开
What about the truth?
你说啥来着
What did you say?
我刚在想我们是否需要长笛
I was just wondering if we need flutes.
谁会吹长笛啊  你会吗
Who plays flute? Do you play flute?
露易丝  刚刚有个门卫问我在这儿干嘛
Louise, some janitor just asked me what I was doing here.
我当时慌了  我说我是个医生
I panicked; I said I was a doctor.
有人问起的话  就说我是格伦・维涅斯
So if anyone asks, I'm Dr. Glen Wellness.
我在韩国服役过
I served in Korea.
可以独自诊断伤员伤情
I handled a triage alone.
要是有人问的话你就这么说
Just if anyone asks.
就说我在出租车后座接生过三胞胎
I delivered triplets in the back of a cab, if anyone asks.
舒娜老师  我知道我被关在这儿的原因
Ms. Schnurr, I want to say I totally understand why I'm in here.
我太无礼了
I was disrespectful.
我没按规矩办事  天哪
I was out of line, and oh, my God,
你动过那幅画吗
did you move that picture?
你动作真快
You are fast.
我练过武术的
I do martial arts.
看出来了
It shows.
你好  嗨
Hello, hi.
你长得可真  矮呀
Oh, aren't you short?
来  跟我来
Here, follow me.
好了  让我们来告诉这些人
All right, let's show these people
只有人象之爱
that if it ain't man-on-elephant love,
才值得一唱
it ain't worth singing about.
注意  各位
Attention, everyone.
我们为大家准备了特别的东西
We have a very special treat for you.
这是一出音乐情景再现
It's a musical re-imagenactment
再现的正是发生在托马斯・爱迪生
of the very uplifting story
和托普西大象之间的感人故事
of Thomas Edison and Topsy the elephant.
*说起托马斯・爱迪生*
*They say Thomas Edison*
*人们都称他为将人类带入新纪元的人*
*He's the man to get us into this century*
*我就是爱迪生*
*And that man is me*
*人们会说  所有*
*They'll say all...*
发生什么事了  露易丝到哪儿去了
What's going on? Where's Louise?
怎么蒂娜和吉恩的声音
And why do Tina and Gene
听着像盖尔和费舍奥德先生
sound like Gayle and Mr. Fischoeder?
这是科学  鲍勃
It's science, Bob.
科学就是要让人不知所云
You're not supposed to understand it.
好吧
Okay.
求你了  舒娜老师
Come on, Ms. Schnurr.
放我出去吧
Let me out of here.
这是我的使命
This is my destiny.
我这儿在吃酸奶呢
Shh, I'm trying to eat this yogurt.
嘟嘟  送书来咯
Toot, toot, here comes books.
让人起鸡皮疙瘩的图书管理员
Creepy librarian.
我认识你吗
Do I know you?
是你跟我说的托普西的事啊
You told me about Topsy.
我跟所有人都说过
I tell everyone about Topsy.
这是你要的书
So, here's the book you requested.
鸡仔文学  好东西
Good stuff, chick lit.
鸡仔文学指由女性撰写
并且主要面向二三十岁的单身职场女性的文学作品
你一定得帮帮我
Oh, you've got to help me.
告诉她我非去科学展不可
Tell her I've got to go to the fair.
告诉她我非打败丁克勒不可
Tell her I've got to take Dinkler down.
别把我扯进来
Shh, leave me out of it.
都是因你而起
You started it.
我只负责挑事端  收尾我可不管
I start, I don't finish things.
这就是我唯一的缺点
That's my one flaw.
酸奶味道还好吗
So, how's that yogurt?
好啊  我不管你了
Fine! Forget you!
我谁也不管了  吃你的酸奶去吧
Forget all of you! Eat your yogurt!
我自己逃了
I'm busting out!
把东西准备好  泰迪  这事我干定了
Get everything ready, Teddy, because this is happening.
我去找对讲机  等我说"开始"的时候
I'll get to the radio and when I say "Hit it,"
你就使出吃奶的劲儿启动装置
you hit it with everything you've got.
明白了吗
Capisce?
等等  别丢下我
Wait, don't leave me.
好吧  没事的
Okay, everything's all right.
你是格伦・维涅斯
You're Dr. Glen Wellness.
什么事都难不倒你
You can handle anything.
你的医学院入学考试拿了全美最高分
Hell, you got the highest MCATs in the state.
*但我却从未发现*
*But I never noticed*
*她那性感的大腿曲线*
*The curve of her trunk*
*但我却从未发现*
*And I never noticed*
*他发明的电子垃圾*
*His electric junk*
*也许我们找到了*
*We might just have found*
*电子之爱*
*Electric love*
*Electric love...*
这真是吉恩写的吗
Wow, did Gene write this?
上帝  我真羡慕他们的爱情
God, I want what they have.
太浪漫了
It's so romantic.
*电子之爱*
*Electric love*
*Electric love...*
*我们天生一对*
*Fits like a glove*
接下来发生的才是真相  各位
This is what really happened, people.
这个人  托马斯・爱迪生
This man, Thomas Edison,
把那头美丽的大象托普西
sentenced Topsy, that beautiful elephant,
电击电死了
to die by electrocution.
这就是你的偶像  丁克勒
Here's your hero, Dinkler.
开始
Hit it!
是你吗  露易丝
Is that you, Louise?
-开始  -我在这下面待了好久
- Hit it! - I've been down here so long.
外面现在是什么情况
What's it like out there?
大家还是一样滑稽可笑吗
Are people still the same with their funny ways?
泰迪  开始
Teddy, hit it!
对哦  我们的计划
Oh, right, the thing we're doing.
蒂娜
Tina!
Tina?
我没事
I'm okay.
-我的天哪  -谢天谢地  蒂娜
- Oh! Oh, God. - Oh, thank God. Tina.
我还以为我们不演电刑那一场了
I thought we weren't doing the death scene,
但我看见有火花  就条件反射了
but I saw the sparks and went with it.
我演得像吗
Was I convincing?
像  像得很
Yes, very.
天哪  我差点电死我姐姐
Oh, my God, I almost electrocuted my sister.
-我也变成爱迪生了  -别妄想了
- I've become Edison. - Oh, you wish.
是的  他电死过动物
So he electrocuted animals.
那又怎样
So what?
好像你们自己都很完美似的
As if everyone here is so perfect.
我们亲得太忘我了
Oh, got a little caught up in the moment.
我们坠入爱河了
We're in love!
我们是坠入爱河的情侣
We're a couple in love!
这一天终于来临了
It's really happening finally!
-谢谢你  上帝  -先闪了
- Thank you, God! - Got to go.
你该叫我唱歌的  不过无所谓了
Could have asked me to sing, but whatever.
你知道的  我唱歌也不错的
You know, I could've sung it.
露易丝  你是不是有话要跟你姐姐说
Louise, is there something you want to say to your sister?
蒂娜  抱歉我差点杀了你
Tina, I'm sorry I nearly killed you.
丁克勒的事让我丧失理智了
I got carried away with the Dinkler thing,
最终的结果是还不错啦
which worked out pretty well, but still,
但我还是不该差点杀了你
I shouldn't have almost killed you.
没关系  这是托普西想看到的结果
It's okay; This is how Topsy would have wanted it,
不过在它的版本里有更多人被它踩死
but with more trampling people.
还有吉恩  我也要对你说抱歉
And, Gene, I'm sorry to you, too.
你的歌很棒
Your song was really good.
我知道  而且还没出现屁声
I know, and without a single fart sound.
天哪  我忘记加屁声了
Oh, my God, I forgot the fart sounds!
怎么样
How'd we do?
你差点杀了我女儿
Well, you almost killed my daughter.
所以  不怎么样
So yeah, not great.
对不起
Oh, wow, sorry about that.
你看见那边的调料腕带了吗
Hey, did you check out that Spiceps thing?
-是不是很酷  -真的吗
- Cool, huh? - Really?
-我是这么觉得的  -没错
- I thought so. - Yeah.
鉴于丁克勒老师这会儿正在厕所哭呢
Since Mr. Dinkler is in the bathroom, crying,
就由我来宣布科学展的获胜者
I'm stepping in to announce the science fair winners.
获得第二名的是安迪和奥利的
Second place goes to "How Many Hairs Up There?",
"我有多少根头发"
by Andy and Ollie Pesto.
天哪  我要谢谢奥利
Oh, my God! I want to thank Ollie.
我要谢谢安迪
I want to thank Andy.
-我要谢谢奥利  -我要谢谢安迪
- I want to thank Ollie. - I want to thank Andy.
那都能得第二名  开玩笑吧
That got second? That's ridiculous.
而蓝绶带的获得者是  调料
And the blue ribbon goes to "Spice..."
这个我看不懂
uh, I can't read this.
调料胸带  调料胸带
Spice Rack! Spice Rack!
调料腕带  调料腕带
Spiceps, Spiceps!
-调料胸带  -调料腕带
- Spice Rack! - Spiceps!
-腕带  -胸带
- Spiceps! - Ow! Rack!
*电子之爱*
*Electric love*